National Council On Household Employment Records 5226
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series V. Publications and Miscellaneous Manuscripts
  - Hurst, Marion. Household Employees Handbook, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 95)
    Trade and Industrial Division of Vocational Education. Oklahoma City, Oklahoma. l55 p
  - "Cost of Living Study, Household Employees" (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Industrial Department - Denver Y.W.C.A. Statistician - Leonard J. Bisbing. Compilations by W.A.A. - Project Number 41567. no date. l8 p
  - Industrial Women's Organizations, Standing Joint Committee of. Reports On Hospitals and the Patient and a Domestic Workers' Charter, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    to be presented to the National Conference of Labour Women, Blackpool, June 2,3, and 4, l93l. Labour Party, Transport House, Smith Square, London. 22 p
  - "A Movement in Home Economics For Self-Supporting Young Women & Girls." (Box 5, Folder 3)
    International Child Welfare League, Inc. Comm. on Home Economics. New York, no date. 4 p
  - Johnson, Eleanor. Household Employment in Chicago, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    U.S. Department of Labor, Women's Bureau. Bulletin of the Women's Bureau, No. l06. G.P.O., Washington, D.C. 62 p
  - Keen, George. "Essentials of Co-operative Success.", 1933 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Labour Annual, of the Alberta Labour News. Brantford, Ontario: The Co-operative Union of Canada. 4 p
  - Keliher, Alice V., editor. Household Workers, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    New York: Harper & Brothers Publishers. 56 p
  - Kemmerer, Edwin Walter. The Gold Standard - Its Nature and Future, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    New York: Economists' National Committee on Monetary Policy. l8 p
  - Kerr, Clark and Paul S. Taylor. "The Self Help Cooperatives in California.", 1935 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Reprinted from Essays in Social Economics. California: University of California Press, May l935. 34 p
  - Labour Party. What's Wrong With Domestic Service? We Want to Know What You Think (Box 5, Folder 9)
    London: Transport House, Smith Square, no date. 8 p
  - League Light. Easter Greeting, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Brooklyn, New York, March 1929. 24 p
  - Lebengood, Anna M. and Amey Watson. "Training Household Workers in Pennsylvania.", 1938 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Pennsylvania Social Work, Vol. V, No. 2, October l938. Harrisburg, Pennsylvania. pp. 44-50
  - Legal Aid Society. Domestic Employment, A Handbook., 1908 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    New York, 24 p
  - Lindsay, Malvina. "When We Consider the Servant Problem - From the Standpoint of the Modern Houseworker.", 1930 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    The Forecast, Vol. XL, No. 3, September 1930. pp. 135-136, 176
  - Livingstone, Helen. Training for Household Occupations in the American Home, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Fourth Edition. New York City, l936. l02 p
  - Lusby, Ruth M. "Teaching Employer-Employee Relations.", 1929 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Journal of Home Economics, Vol. 21, No. 11, November 1929 pp 824-826
  - Lyle, Mary S. and Rua Van Horn. Homemaking Education Programs for Adults, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Washington, D.C.: U.S. Department of the Interior. Office of Education. Vocational Education Bulletin No. l95. Home Economics Series No. 22, l938. l25 p.
  - MacDonald, Alice. "Do You Know Your Place?", 1941 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    Junior League Magazine, April 1941. pp 28,62
  - "Housework, The Feudal Occupation", 1941 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    Junior League Magazine, April 1941, pp. 38-39, 56
  - "Where Do We Go From Here?", 1941 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    Junior League Magazine, May 1941
  - MacLeod, Sarah. Housecleaning Made Easier, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    U.S. Department of Agriculture, Farmers' Bulletin No. ll80. Washington, D.C., G.P.O., l933. Issued January l92l; revised May l926. l8 p
  - Magnus, Erna. Domestic Workers in Philadelphia: Summary and Conclusion (Box 5, Folder 21)
    7 p. not dated
  - "Negro Domestic Workers in Private Homes In Baltimore. ", 1941 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    Reprinted from Social Security Bulletin, Vol. 4, No. l0. Federal Security Agency, Social Security Board. Washington, D.C., October l94l. (G.P.O.: 1942). 7 p
  - McCormick, Ada. "Exit the Cook.", 1931 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    Good Housekeeping, April 1931. 4p
  - McGregor, Virginia. A Study of the Wages of Household Employees in the Y.W.C.A.'s of Thirteen Illinois Communities., 1939 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    Chicago, Illinois, 13p
  - McGrew, Lilian Culbertson and J.R. Hawke. A Study of Household Employment in Omaha, Nebraska, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    Made jointly by the Omaha Y.W.C.A. and the Omaha Public Schools. 47 p
  - Millar's Chicago Letter. "Household Employment", 1939 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    Vol. 1 #29, October 18, 1939. 8p
  - Minneapolis Public Schools. Program of Studies in the Girl's Vocational High School, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    11p
  - Moffett, Carol Willis. House Cleaning: Management & Methods, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    U.S. Department of Agriculture, Farmers' Bulletin No. l834. Washington, D.C.: G.P.O. 22 p
  - "To Promote Efficiency Among Household Workers, So That Their Working Conditions Generally May Be Improved and Standardized.", 1937 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    National Committee of Household Workers. Bulletin I & III., Volume I. October l, l937. 8 p.; February l, l938. 4 p. Cincinnati, Ohio. 8 p
  - National Committee on Employer-Employee Relationships in the Home, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    Summary of Second Conference. New York City, April 13 & 14, l93l. l9 p
  - National Committee on Household Employment Bulletin, 1934-1936 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - National Committee on Prisons and Prison Labor, 1927 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    Report of a Survey made by the Committee on Care and Training of Delinquent Women and Girls of. Industries for Correctional Institutions for Women. New York. l44 p
  - National Council on Household Employment Bulletin, 1939-1941 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - A Voluntary Agreement in Household Employment, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    The Committee on Household Employment of the Y.W.C.A. of Chicago. April, l942. 3 p
  - Women Are Cleaning House! (Box 5, Folder 35)
    Haverford, Pennsylvania, no date. 4 p
  - National Management Council of the U.S.A. Home Management Papers, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    Seventh International Management Congress. Washington, D.C., September 23, l938. Baltimore, Maryland: Waverly Press, Inc., l938. l2l p
  - National Management Council of the U.S.A. Proceedings, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    September l9-23, l938. Baltimore, Maryland: The Waverly Press, Inc., l938. 339 p
  - Circular of Information for the Twelfth Annual Session, 1921-1922 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    National Training School for Women and Girls, Inc. Washington, D.C.
  - My Vocation With Special Reference To The Problems Faced by Negro Youth. (Box 5, Folder 39)
    National Urban League. Department of Industrial Relations. New York, no date. 16 p
  - Today and Tomorrow. Statement of the Purposes and Plans of the Fourth Vocational Opportunity Campaign to Improve the Status of Negro Workers, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    May 7-l4, l933. New York, NY 3 p
  - The Need of Organization Among Household Employees, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    National Urban League. Workers' Bureau. The Workers'Council Bulletin No. l6. May 28, l937. New York. 7 p
  - "American at Work.", 1940 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    National Vocational Guidance Association. Broadcast of January 9, l940. Produced by CBS Department of Education. Bulletin No. 35. The Household Worker. New York, l940. 23 p
  - National Women's Trade Union League of America Life and Labor Bulletin, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    Vol. IX, No. l0 - Serial No. 97, December l93l. 4 p.
  - Life and Labor Bulletin, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    No. 19, February 1941. 4 p
  - National Youth Administraton. Resident Home - Management School, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    Binghamton, New York, Broome County Advisory Council and the Binghamton Women's Organizations, February l938. 4 p
  - National Youth Administration for Kentucky. Domestic Service, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    Louisville, Kentucky, NYS Guidance Project, Division of Educational Aid, 8/1/37. 64 p
  - National Youth Administration of Illinois. Occupational Information, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    Research Report on Domestic Occupations. May l2, l936. Chicago, Illinois. 37 p
  - Needleman, Rae L. "Are Domestic Workers Coming of Age.", 1939 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    American Federationist, Vol. 46, No. l0, October l939. pp. l070-l075
  - New York Household-Placement Association. Warning, Danger To All Employers of Domestic Labor (Box 5, Folder 49)
    New York, 6 p. No date
  - Miscellaneous Series. Help-Wanted Advertising., 1939-1940 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    New York State Division of Placement and Unemployment Insurance. Bureau of Research and Statistics. Statistics Report No. 3. New York City. l03 p
  - New York State. National Youth Administration. Federal Security Agency. Resident Work Center Directory, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    February l, l94l. 57 p
  - New York Women's Trade Union League. Annual Report, 1939-1940 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    22p
  - The New Step. A Guidebook for Pupils, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    Oklahoma City Board of Education. Separate High Schools, Oklahoma City, Oklahoma. 47 p
  - Pasadena Study of Domestic Occupations, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    Pasadena League of Women Voters. Department of Economic Welfare.. Pasadena, December l937. 23 p
  - Pennsylvania State Employment Service. Household Employment As A Profession (Box 5, Folder 55)
    Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, no date. 3p
  - Report of the Conference on Household Employment, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    Frick Training School, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. 26 p
  - Digest of Findings of the Philadelphia Study of Household Employment. (Box 5, Folder 57)
    Philadelphia Council on Household Occupations. Philadelphia. No date. 8 p
  - Philadelphia Institute on Household Occupations Final Report, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    August 1939, 71 p
  - Proposals For A Voluntary Agreement in Household Employment, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    Philadelphia Standards Committee of the W.P.A. Household Demonstration Project. June l938. 4 p
  - Pidgeon, Mary Elizabeth and Margaret Thompson Mettert. Employed Women and Family Support, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    U.S. Department of Labor. Women's Bureau. No. l68. G.P.O., Washington, D.C. 57 p
  - "Problems of the Home, Discussed by Outlook Readers", 1912 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    Outlook, September 14, 1912, pp 71-82
  - Robinson, Elizabeth V. House Care Manual, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 62)
    State of New York. Department of Correction, Westfield State Farm, Bedford Hills, New York. ll5 p
  - Robinson, Grace. "My Maid - Impossible Female. A Search for the Perfect Servant.", 1930 (Box 5, Folder 63)
    Liberty, March 22, l930, pp. 52-60
  - Robinson, Mary V. A New Program for Household Workers, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 64)
    Presented at the Panel On New and Specialized Services of the Convention of International Association of Public Employment Service, Kansas City, Missouri, May l6, l940. Washington, U.S. Department of Labor, Women's Bureau. 7 p
  - Domestic Workers and Their Employment Relations, 1924 (Box 5, Folder 65)
    A Study Based on the Records of the Domestic Efficiency Association of Baltimore, Maryland. U.S. Department of Labor. Women's Bureau. Bulletin of the Women's Bureau, No. 39. Washington, G.P.O. 87 p
  - "Why Workers Object to Household Employment.", 1937 (Box 5, Folder 66)
    Labor Information Bulletin, Vol. IV, No. l0, October l937. pp. l2-l3
  - Robinson, Selma. "Mrs. Spencer's Maid is Leaving!", 1939 (Box 5, Folder 67)
    Good Housekeeping, March l939. pp. 29-29, 82-88. p. 9
  - Roelofs, Henrietta. "Studies of Labor Problems in Household Employment", 1916 (Box 5, Folder 68)
    Reprinted from the Bulletin of the American Home Economics Association, Series 4, No. 5, December l9l6. Household Employment Commission of the National Board of the Young Women's Christian Association, New York City. pp. 46-56
  - "The Road to Trained Service in the Household"., 1915 (Box 5, Folder 69)
    Y.W.C.A., Bulletin #2, 1915, 8 pp. multicopy, 11 pp
  - Ross, Ishbel. "The Vanishing Domestic.", 1942 (Box 5, Folder 70)
    Coronet, January l942. pp. 112-ll6
  - Darling Resident Center. Information for Applicants. (Box 6, Folder 35)
    U.S. National Youth Administration. Westchester, Pennsylvania. No date. 12 p.
  - School of Scientific Housekeeping, 1940-1941 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    New York, no date. 35 p
  - Schools for Women Workers in Industry, 1929 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Reprint Bryn Mawr Alumnae Bulletin, December l929. ll p
  - Seeley, Evelyn. "Our Feudal Housewives.", 1938 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    The Nation, May 28, l938. pp. 6l3-6l5
  - Sergel, Ruth. The Women In the House: Stories of Household Employment, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    New York: Women's Press. 149 p
  - "Servant in the Home.", 1931 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Fortune, Vol. IV No. 6, December 1931. pp 44-47
  - "Servants are Humans." (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Anonymous. The Forum, pp 165-170, no date
  - Smith, Florence P. State Minimum-Wage Laws and Orders: An Analysis, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    Bulletin of the Women's Bureau, No. l67. Washington, D.C.: G.P.O. 34 p
  - School and Employment Standards for Household Service (Box 6, Folder 8)
    Smith's Vocational School. Household Arts Department. Northhampton, Massachusetts, 6 p. No date
  - Snyder, Eleanor M. Job Histories of Women Workers at the Summer Schools, 1931-34 and 1938, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    Washington: U.S. Department of Labor, Women's Bureau, Bulletin No. 174, 25 p
  - Home Assistants: Vocational Training Program, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    State Board of Control for Vocational Education. Trade and Industrial and Home Economics Division. Bulletin No. 247. Lansing, Michigan. 75 p
  - Stitt, Louise. Household Employment: The Problem Nationally, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    Symposium on Household Employment held in New York City, November l939. Haverford, Pennsylvania, National Council on Household Employment. l6 p
  - Stocks, Ester H. A Community Home Assistants Experiment. An Experimental Demonstration of the Institute for the Co-ordination of Women's Interests, 1928 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    Smith College, Northampton, Massachusetts. 30 p
  - "New Days - New Ways Women Are Cleaning House.", 1939 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    Symposium on Household Employment, Report of. Held in New York, N.Y., November 28, l939. 52 p
  - Tolman, Edna. "So You Can't Keep a Maid!", 1943 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    The Saturday Evening Post, October 9, l943. pp. 22-23, 9l-93
  - Trade and Industrial Education. Guideposts for Employers. (Box 6, Folder 15)
    Prepared from Conferences held at the Y.W.C.A. Sponsored by the Employers Advisory Committee of the Household Employee Training Service of the Oklahoma City Public Schools, Y.M.C.A. and Trade and Industrial Department. No date. 11p
  - "Training for Household Employment.", 1940 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    l. The W.P.A. Program by Florence Kerr. 2. In Canada by Isabella Alexander. Journal of Home Economics, Vol. 32, No. 7, Sept. l940. American Home Economics Association, Washington, D.C. pp. 437-442
  - "Holidays on Vacation for Household Workers: Bulletin Survey to Report on Programs in l9 Cities.", 1947 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    U.S. Department of Labor. Labor Information Bulletin, April l947. Washington, D.C.: G.P.O. 2 p
  - Domestic Workers and Legislation, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    U.S. Department of Labor. Women's Bureau. Washington, April l940. 6 p
  - Domestic Workers and Legislation, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    Washington, February 1941. 6p
  - Household Employment: An Outlook for Study Groups, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    Washington, November 1940. 56p
  - "Household Workers Earnings and Outgo", 1941 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    The Woman Worker, November 1941, Washington. p15
  - Old Age Insurance for Household Workers, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    Bulletin No. 220, Washington. 20 p
  - Reading List of References on Household Employment, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    Washington, September 1935. 19 p
  - Reading List of References on Household Employment, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    Washington, 15 p
  - Reading List of References on Household Employment, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    Bulletin no. 154. Washington. 17 p
  - Reading List of References on Household Employment, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    Supplement to Women's Bureau Bulletin 154. Washington, November 1940. 11 p
  - The Effect of Minimum-Wage Determinations in Service Industries, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    Bulletin no. 166. Washington. 44 p
  - What It Is, What It Does, What It Publishes, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    Washington, revised August 1941. 10 p
  - Women at Work, A Century of Industrial Change, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    Bulletin no. 161. Washington. 80 p
  - An Educational Program for Household Employment, Trade and Industrial and Home Economics Education., 1935 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    U.S. Department of the Interior. Office of Education. Vocational Division. Misc. 1717. November 1935. 56 p
  - Household Employment Problems: A Handbook for Round-Table Discussions Among Household Employers., 1937 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    Home-Economics Education. Misc. l97l. September l937. Washington, D.C. 58 p
  - Vocational Training for Household Employment, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    Misc. 1613. Washington. 11 p
  - Official Directory, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    U.S. Federal Works Agency. Works Projects Administration. Central - Regional and State Administrative Offices. December l, l940. l8 p
  - Housekeeping Aide Circular. W.P.A. Technical Series Welfare Circular No. 3, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    U.S. Federal Works Agency. Works Projects Administration. Division of Community Service Programs. September l0, l94l. Washington, D.C. 30 p
  - Household Employment Problems: A Handbook for Round-Table Discussions Among Household Employers, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    U.S. Office of Education. Federal Security Agency. Home-Economics Education. Misc. l97l. September l937, Reissued November l939. Washington, D.C. 58 p
  - U.S. Women's Bureau. Woman Worker, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    Vol. XIX, No. 2, March 1939
  - Home Economics in the W.P.A. Program. (Box 6, Folder 38)
    U.S. Work Projects Administration, Professional and Service Division. Washington, no date. 7 p.
  - Household Service Demonstration Circular No. l, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    U.S. Works Projects Progress Administration. Divison of Women's and Professional Projects. Household Service Demonstration Projects. W.P.A. Series. Washington, D.C., July 6, l937. 37 p
  - Washington League of Women Shoppers. Household Occupation in the District of Columbia (Box 6, Folder 40)
    Washington, D.C. l7 p
  - Watson, Amey E., PhD. "Employer-Employee Relationships in the Home.", 1929 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    The Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science. Philadelphia, May l929. Publication No. 2284. l2 p
  - Household Employment and National Defense, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    New York: The Womans Press. November l940. pp. 474, 476-477, 48l.
  - "Household Employment in Outline.", 1940 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    Reprinted from the Womans Press Magazine, January l940. l5 p
  - Household Employment in Philadelphia, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    U.S. Department of Labor. Women's Bureau. Bulletin of the Women's Bureau No. 93. Washington, D.C., G.P.O., l932. 88 p
  - "The Responsibility of the Home Economist for Improving Employer-Employee Relationships in the Home.", 1939 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    Journal of Home Economics, Vol. 3l, No. 2, February l939. 3 p
  - Watson, Dr. Amey E. and Helen Goodspeed. "A New Pattern in Democratic Living.", 1941 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    Whats New In Home Economics, Vol. V, No. XI, July l94l. Chicago, Illinois, l94l. pp. l2-13
  - Watson, Dr. Amey E. and Dorothy P. Wells. Well-Managed Employer-Employee Relationships in the Home, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 47)
    Seventh International Management Congress. Washington, D.C. Home Management Section. pp. 63-66
  - Wells, Dorothy P. "Household Employees-l,500,000 Women.", 1938 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    Reprinted from Occupations, the Vocational Guidance Magazine, February l938. 6 p
  - Household Employment, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    Reprinted from the Womans Press Magazine, October l934. l p
  - "The Y.M.C.A. and Household Employment", 1935 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    Journal of Home Economics, Vol. 27, No. 9, November 1935. 3 p
  - Wells, Dorothy P. and Carol Biba. Fair and Clear in the Home: A Symposium on Household Employment, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    New York: The Womans Press. 79 p
  - West, Elizabeth S. Housework as a Profession, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 52)
    The Woman's Press, February 1938
  - West Virginia State Employment Service affiliated with Social Security Board, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 53)
    March-April l940. Vol. 6, No. 3 & 4. 30 p
  - White, Marie. Duties and Responsibilities of the General Household Employee: Some Bases for Determining Content for Vocational Courses in Household Employment, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 54)
    U.S. Department of the Interior. Office of Education. Vocational Educational Bulletin No. l94. Home Economics Series No. 2l. Washington, D.C: G.P.O. 32 p
  - Williams, Harriet Walton. Manual for Coordinators of Part-time Home Service Program, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 55)
    Department of Industrial Education. College of Education. University of Kentucky. Lexington, Kentucky. January l94l. 27 p
  - Woldman, Elinore R. Care of Children In Their Homes Through Supervised Homemaker Service, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 56)
    Reprint from the Child-Monthly Bulletin, September l940. 3 p
  - Suggested Standards for Employment: General House Worker., 1938 (Box 6, Folder 57)
    Women's City Club of New York. Committee on Labor and Industry. New York, N.Y. December l938. 4 p
  - Report of a Two Years' Experiment in Social Economics., 1903-1905 (Box 6, Folder 58)
    Woman's Education Association. Committee on Domestic Economy. Household Aid Company. Boston. 21 p
  - Woodward, Ellen S. "The W.P.A. Prepares Women for Housework.", 1938 (Box 6, Folder 59)
    Reprint from Occupations, the Vocational Guidance Magazine, December l938. 4 p
  - It Can Happen In Your Home, 32,000 Deaths Each Year From Home Accidents (Box 6, Folder 60)
    Workmen's Compensation for Household Employees, Committee on. New York City, N.Y. No date. 5 p
  - W.P.A. Technical Series. Household Service Demonstration Circular No. l, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 61)
    Works Progress Administration. Division of Women's and Professional Projects. Household Service Demonstration Projects. Washington, D.C. July 6, 1937. 37 p
  - Young, Donald PhD. "The Modern American Family.", 1932 (Box 6, Folder 62)
    The Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, Vol. l60, March l932. 256 p
  - Young Women's Christian Association. Domestic Service Questionnaire, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 63)
    Occasional Papers. No. 3 and appendix. March l933. New York, N.Y. 8 p
  - First Report of the Committee on Household Employment to the Fifth National Convention, 1915 (Box 6, Folder 64)
    Los Angeles, California, May 5-11, 1915. 34 p
  - Statement on Training, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 65)
    Suggestions from Subcommittee on Household Employment of the Public Affairs Committee of the National Board of the Y.W.C.A. New York, NY. 3 p
  - The Y.W.C.A. Trade School, 1934-1935 (Box 6, Folder 66)
    New York, 32 p
  - Household Employment Mass Meeting, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 67)
    Young Women's Christian Association and Women's Clubs. March 23, 1938. Seattle, Washington. 6 p
  - Suggestions for Better Household Employer-Employee Relations, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 68)
    Y.W.C.A. Comm. on the Cleveland Y.W.C.A. Cleveland, 1937. 2 p
- Series VI. MISCELLANEOUS MANUSCRIPTS
  - Alsop, Natalie. no title (Box 6, Folder 69)